flareaudio.com 2017-10-02

# Privacy & Cookie Policy | Flare Audio Ltd

At Flare Audio®, we respect your concerns about privacy and value the relationship we have with you.

For the purposes of this policy, Flare means Flare Audio Limited, with registered offices at Unit 8, Chartwell Business Centre, Chartwell Road, Lancing, West Sussex, United Kingdom BN41 8FB.

Like many companies, we use technology on our website to collect information that helps us enhance your online experience.

The cookies we use at Flare® allow our website to work, and to help us to understand what information and advertising is most useful to visitors.

## THIS COOKIE POLICY EXPLAINS:

  * What cookies are
  * What information we collect and why
  * The type of cookies we use
  * How long cookies are stored on your device
  * How to manage cookies
  * What happens if you reject all cookies
  * Changes to the cookie policy
  * How to contact us

## WHAT COOKIES ARE

A cookie is a text file containing information which is downloaded to your computer or mobile device when you visit a website. Cookies are useful because they allow websites to recognise a user's device. Cookies are then sent back to the originating website on each subsequent visit, or to another website that recognises that cookie. You can find more information about cookies at: [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

When we refer to Cookies throughout this Policy, we intend to cover all similar devices including web beacons and log files. For more information on those additional tools, please read our Glossary.

## WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND WHY

Part of creating an enjoyable and lasting experience for our customers is to use cookies to process information in order to better understand what you want from our site.

Examples of the types of information we collect via cookies may include:

  * how many users visit the Flare® website, how often the site is visited, the pages visited on the site, click-through on the site and the total time spent on the site;
  * whether you have visited our website before or if you are a new visitor;
  * the website visited before the Flare® site;
  * your viewing preferences (e.g. layout, sizing preferences, language, etc.);
  * your purchases and orders; and
  * your username, password, browser type and IP address, so we can recognise you on future visits.

Please note that we do not collect your name or e-mail address via cookies.

In addition, cookies help us to:

  * customise your visit: we may use information from your visit to help improve your next visit to our site;
  * customise the advertising and marketing messages you receive on this site either from ourselves or from third parties. This could involve identifying website features in which you have an interest, and recommending accessories for your Flare® products. Our goal is to provide you with what you want as quickly and easily as possible; and
  * look at customer trends: we compile information from thousands of customer visits and analyse it as a whole. This kind of study focuses on identifying trends among the many visitors to our site rather than analysing information about any individual customer.

## THE TYPE OF COOKIES WE USE

When you use our website, the following categories of cookies may be set on your device:

### First-party cookies

These cookies are set by Flare®. For the most part, they are strictly necessary to enable you to move around the website and use its features.

  * Strictly necessary cookies – These cookies are set by Flare® and enable you to move about the site or to receive certain requested features, such as allowing you to place orders on the website.
  * Analytics cookies – These cookies are set by Flare® to collect statistical (aggregated and anonymous) information about the use of the website by you and other visitors. This information allows Flare® to enhance the functionality of the website.

### Third-party cookies

In addition to our use of these applications, certain third parties and affiliates may set and access cookies on your computer, and in conjunction with web beacons.

  * Strictly necessary cookies – These cookies enable useful services and functionalities, for example the online chat support.
  * Online behavioral advertising cookies – These cookies collect information about your browsing habits, product and services preferences. This information will allow Flare® and advertising networks we work with to display relevant ads in the most appropriate places on partner websites and on Flare®'s websites. For example, third parties or affiliates may administer Flare® banner advertising programs on a non-Flare® website.

How long cookies are stored on your device

The length of time cookies are stored on your machine can vary, but they generally fall into two categories: temporary or persistent.

### Temporary cookies

We use temporary session cookies on all of our secure pages to assign and store a session ID to you so that you can move uninterrupted between the areas of our site. This session ID is also used for internal reporting purposes. It is not personally identifiable to you, and this type of cookie does not leave any retrievable information on your hard drive. Most of our first party cookies are session cookies which expire when you close your internet browser.

### Persistent cookies

Our first party analytics cookies and third party cookies are persistent cookies because they are used to help us understand visitor patterns over a longer term or to provide additional functions you have requested in relation to site customization and saved or stored content. They can be stored on your computer for 24 hours, a week, or several years, depending on the function they're helping to perform.

## HOW TO MANAGE COOKIES

If you don't want to receive certain categories of cookies on our websites, you can use the following tool to opt-out of them. Please note that we will need to set a cookie so that we can remember your choices when you next visit the website from the same browser.

At the present time it is not technically possible for us to allow you to carry your settings with you between your browsers and devices (i.e. your computer or smartphone) so you will need to change these settings independently on each browser/device you use. You will need to set these preferences every time you use a new browser or a new device.

### Strictly necessary cookies

These cookies are set by Flare® and enable you to move about the site or to receive certain requested features, such as allowing you to place orders on the website.

### Analytics cookies

These cookies are set by Flare® in order to collect statistical (aggregated and anonymous) information about the use of the website. This information allows Flare® to enhance the functionality of the website.

### Strictly necessary cookies set by third parties

These cookies enable useful services and functionalities, for example the online chat support, and are offered by Flare®'s partners.

### Online behavioural advertising cookies

These cookies are set by Flare® or by advertising partners in order to collect several pieces of information about your browsing habits, product and services preferences. This information will allow Flare® and partners to display relevant ads on partner websites and on Flare®'s websites.

In addition, you are free to manage your cookies via your web browser. You can always set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, which gives you the option to decide whether or not to accept it. You can remove cookies from your machine at any time.

If you are concerned about having cookies on your device, follow the directions below to manage cookies stored on your device.

If you are using **Internet Explorer (IE) 9.0+** :

**To disable cookies:**

  * Go to 'Tools' in the menu bar which should drop down then click on 'Internet Options'
  * Click on 'Privacy' Tab on top
  * Move the slider up to the desired Privacy Level

**To delete existing cookies:**

  * Go to 'Tools' in the menu bar which should drop down then click on 'Internet Options'
  * Click on 'General' tab which should be under 'Browsing History' and click 'Delete'

If you are using **Firefox 2.0+ / 3.0+ / 4.0+** :

**To disable cookies:**

  * Go to 'Tools' in the menu bar
  * Click on 'Options'
  * Click on 'Privacy Tab'
  * Disable the box that says 'Accept Cookies From sites'

**To delete existing cookies:**

  * Go to 'Tools' in the menu bar
  * Click on 'Options'
  * Click on 'Privacy Tab'
  * Click on 'Clear Now'
  * Select 'Cookies'
  * Click on 'Clear Private Data Now'

If you are using **Google Chrome**

**To disable cookies:**

  * Go to 'Tools Menu'
  * Click on 'Options'
  * Click on 'Under the Hood'
  * 'Cookie Setting' should be selected. Once done select 'Block all Cookies'

**To delete existing cookies:**

  * Go to 'Tools Menu'
  * Click on 'Options'
  * Click on 'Under the Hood'
  * Under 'Privacy' section select 'Show Cookies'
  * A new window should open called 'Cookies'. In here you can see all the cookies within your Google Chrome Browser
  * Click on 'Remove All' to remove all traces of cookies
  * If you wish to only remove a certain cookie, simply highlight and click 'Remove'

If you use a web browser not listed above, please refer to your browser's documentation or online help for more information.

## WHAT HAPPENS IF YOU REJECT ALL COOKIES?

You'll still be able to use some parts of our websites. But some useful features will not work if you disable cookies. For example, you will not be able to make purchases.

## CHANGES TO THE POLICY

This policy may be revised from time to time. We will post changes on this website. This policy is specific to Flare® operations and applies to information you submit online as well as through other channels. This policy is here for your convenience and is not intended to create a binding obligation. Should you have any questions, please contact us.

## HOW TO CONTACT US?

If you have any questions or concerns regarding our use of cookies, or if you want to exercise your right to access your data and/or have any information we hold about you rectified, you may contact us .

## GLOSSARY

Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information which are downloaded to your computer or mobile device when you visit a website. Cookies are then sent back to the originating website on each subsequent visit, or to another website that recognizes that cookie.

Log files are web server files (such as domain name or IP address, URL, the http response code, the website from where you visit us and/or the date and duration of your visit) that are automatically created when an internet user visits a site.

Certain pages on our website contain "web beacons" (also known as Internet tags, pixel tags and clear GIFs). A web beacon is an electronic file that usually consists of a single-pixel image. It can be placed on a web page or in an email to transmit information, which could include Personal Information such as the IP address of the computer that downloaded the page on which the beacon appears, the URL of the page on which the beacon appears, the time the page containing the beacon was viewed, the type of browser used to view the page, and the information in cookies sent by a third party.

## PRIVACY POLICY

**Personal Information:** By "Personal Information" we mean any information relating to you and by which you can be identified directly (e.g. your name) or indirectly (e.g. your IP address which we collect when you purchase a product online).

**How we collect your Personal Information:** The following is an overview of some of the means by which we may obtain Personal Information:

Online: Purchases on the Flare® website

Other online interactions (competition and prize draw entries, surveys, etc.)

Offline:Phone and mail.

Product registration cards

**How we use your Personal Information:** In general, the Personal Information will be used for the following purposes:

Processing your orders, answering your questions on Flare® products and services, or providing you with technical updates on our products and services in different areas, such as fulfillment of an order or billing.

Carrying out market studies on the basis of aggregate (not personally identifiable) information in order to improve our products and services. Such market studies may be carried out with the help of external partners processing these data on behalf of Flare®.

Analyzing your Personal Information including your personal preferences in order to provide you with personalized marketing information on Flare® products, services and promotions, as well as on products and services of partners of Flare® selected on the basis of personal preferences, hobbies and interests.

You will receive this information by email, sms, over the phone or by personalized mail only if you have asked to receive such messages from Flare® and its commercial partners.

Flare® may append additional data received from third parties to your Personal Information for analysis and marketing purposes.

Establishing statistics on your use of the website, for marketing and analysis, in order to improve our website and our offers.

Transferring your Personal Information to third parties for the purposes set out below.

**Transfers to third parties:** It may be necessary to transfer your Personal Information (name, address, tel. number, e-mail, preferences, interest) to companies associated with Flare® or its agents, in order for them to carry out order research, purchase processing, analysis and marketing on behalf of Flare®.

In case of a change of control at Flare®, we reserve the right to transfer your Personal Information to any company which would take over any control over Flare's® activities. Please be also advised that Flare® may have to disclose specific information to third parties (courts, administrative bodies, etc.) if required by law.

**How to communicate your preferences or to exercise your rights to have your Personal Information rectified, blocked or deleted:** At the time you provide your Personal Information to Flare® (for example, at the time of purchase), you can express your marketing preferences in respect of the Personal Information (mailing address, e-mail address, phone number) you share with us. Check boxes on the website or on the offline document whereby your Personal Information is collected allow you to opt-in or opt-out of receiving updates on our products and services or on the product and services of our commercial partners. If Flare® has used your data after receiving this information from another company to which you provided your data, you will be able to express your preference at the time Flare® contacts you. You can then always contact Flare® and ask that your information will not be used for direct marketing purposes.

Contact us either by phone on 00 44 (1)903 761 00, by e-mail (info@flareaudio.com) or by post to Flare Audio Limited, Unit 8 Chartwell Business Centre, Chartwell Road, Lancing, West Sussex, BN15 8FB, United Kingdom, to update your Customer Communications preferences or if you want to exercise your rights to access your data and/or have any information we hold about you rectified, blocked or deleted if no longer necessary.

**Changes to the Policy.** This policy may be revised from time to time. We will post changes on this website and inform you via e-mail or mail. If you do not object to such a change within 14 days upon receipt of our information, the new policy will apply. We highlight the effects of no-replies in our communication. In case of objection to the new policy, the old terms shall stay in place.

This Privacy Policy is governed exclusively under the law of the England and Wales.
